Gabriel Silva Pereira

Brazilian, 23 years

Rio de Janeiro – RJ, Brazil

CONTACT

+55021982531688

gabriel.silva.w1n3@gmail.com

https://github.com/W1N3

https://www.linkedin.com/in/gabriel-silva-pereira-8023b31a9

RESUME

Student of the art of computing in life.

Got experience in programming, operations and web development – from the backend to the frontend – from conceptual modelling to the search for technical solutions fit to the context.

Accustomed user of gnu/linux environment inclined to propose solutions that use open source tools.

EDUCATION

Undergradute Degree in Course – Bachelor in Computer Science – DCC – IM - CCMN – UFRJ, admission in 2015, graduation forecast in 2022;

Complete High School with Computer Technician – CEFET/MG – Campus II - Belo Horizonte – admission in 2012, graduation in 2015.

EXPERIENCE

09/2019 - 01/2020 [5 motnhs] - CAPGov (Centro de Apoio a Políticas de Governo) (COPPE/UFRJ)

Role: Scholarship PIBIC

Main activities: Development of frontend part of an existent project with legacy libraries. Tools used: Ionic 1, Angular JS 1.7, GitLab.

04/2017 – **05/2019** [2 anos e 2 mês] - **Media library of (FAU/CLA/UFRJ)**

Role: Scholarship PIBIAC

Main activies: Difusion and debugging of database of the media library. This includes insertion and correction of the data in the system. Debugging and updating of the database system manager, via PhpMyAdmin – MySQL and Web page, via PHP.

10/2016 - 04/2017 [7 meses] - LCI Supervisor (DCC/IM/CCMN/UFRJ)

Role: Scholarship monitoring PAEALIG in servers team

Main activies: Comply with the demand of students and teachers around problems of daily of the laboratory of the computer science graduation. Inside the servers team I developed the maintenance of services and webpages that course provides to the students: dcc.ufrj.br webpage, SSH service, clusterizing of the services using Docker, teachers webpages in the DCC domain, users account by LDAP, etc.

04/2016 – 09/2016 [*6 Meses*] **– ActivUFRJ (NCE/CCMN/UFRJ)**

Role: Scholarship in Pedagogic support (Web development)

Main activities: Programming in Python, Javascript, CSS Responsive, HTML, maintenance and development in the "No-SQL" CouchDB database.

03/2015 – 09/2015 [7 meses] – Codificar Sistemas Tecnológicos Itda.

Role: Web developer Internship

Main activities: Programming in C#, Javascript, CSS, HTML, maintenance and development in the SQL Server database in two projects: concessions integrated system for SETOP/MG for the PwC company, and the performance evaluation system for CODEMIG.

SKILLS

[All items below summarize all technical experience I had until then]

Programming Languages

C, Java, PHP, C#, Python, JavaScript, CSS, HTML, Shell Script;

Frameworks e Libraries

Front-End – VueJS, Bootstrap.js, AngularJS, Ionic, Chart.js, Leaflet;

Back-End – ExpressJS, Tornado Web Server, Laravel;

Databases – PouchDB, CouchDB, PHPMyAdmin, MySQL(MariaDB), SQL Server:

Servers – Docker, Apache(httpd), LDAP, IIS, .NET Framework;

Tools and general notions

Habit in using Linux and a variety of tools in the terminal: Git, Docker, Ssh, etc; Team work with clear communication through Kanban, Trello, Scrum, follow the design pattern, codification and documentation of the team;

Search for solutions with base in technical research(GitHub, StackOverflow, miscellaneous forums) and theoretical knowledge (Techniques and algorithms, data structures, computers architecture, operating systems, computer networking, software engineering) fit to the context;

LANGUAGES

Portuguese (Brazilian) – Native.

English – read well, listen well, write moderately, speak moderately – self-taught, 9 years (since 2011), in development

Rio de Janeiro, 30, October, 2020.